

## **CONTACT**



www.ivabeleva.com



+49 176 57679695



i.beleva@senokol.com



Senokol GmbH Wotanstr. 10, 82110 Germering

#### **FOCUS**

**UX-Strategy & Conceptual Design User Flows** Journey Mapping Scribbles & Wireframing Interactive High-fidelity Prototypes Interaction Design **High-end Aesthetics** Style Guide Design System **Usability Tests** Research User Interviews & Surveys Personas Information Architecture (IA) Agile & Scrum

## **CERTIFICATES**

2023 Design Systems Masterclass, Brad Frost

2021 CareerFoundry **UX Design Certification** 

#### **SCAN ME**



# IVA **BELEVA**

**UX/UI** Designer

Certified UX Designer with a strong background in conceptual and visual design. Experienced in creating custom user-centered design solutions that align business goals with user needs. With constant attention to detail creates simple and intuitive digital products.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **UX/UI Designer & Researcher, Freelance Customer: Virtual Identity AG**

11.2022 - now

Figma

Miro

Adobe Creative Suite

Scrum

ClickUp

Working closely with the Product Owner, I was responsible for unifying the requirements of multiple clients into a white label SaaS product that allows advice seekers to connect with an counsellor.

- Interviewed clients to gather pain points and elaborate requirements
- Created user flows and design concepts
- Delivered wireframes and high-fidelity prototypes
- · Handled well-structured specifications that acted as a bridge between the two international development teams, creating a common understanding
- Developed further the design system
- · Conducted usability tests

# **UX/UI Designer, Freelance Customer: Valtech Mobility, Munich**

02.2022 - 10.2022

Sketch

Abstract

Zeplin

ProtoPie

Miro

Jira

Scrum

As a part of the multi-disciplinary tech team, I have delivered concepts and UI Designs for an end customer facing app for the automobile industry.

- · Created information architecture, user flow diagrams, scribbles and wireframes with Sketch
- Planned and conducted a remote usability test to verify the app features
- · Worked with the end client's design system to ensure consistent visual language. Enhanced the design system with new components to enable new interactions
- · Created icons to create a more intuitive display for specific system messages
- Worked closely with the dev team to ensure well-prepared handoff of the designs, e.g. assets suitable for iOS and Android.

# **UX/UI Designer, Freelance Customer: Seabeck Systems LLC**

07.2021 - 02.2022

Figma

Jira

Confluence

Material UI Design System

Designed intuitive products for Seabeck Systems clients that attracted new prospects and enhanced customer support.

- Analysed requirements with the clients resulting in clear project vision
- Desiged simple and intuitive digital products by applying the design thinking methods to solve difficult design problems, including visualizing complex data in charts & graphs
- · Created information architecture, wireframes, hi-fi prototypes & style guide
- · Checked the technical feasibility of the designs with the development team and where required provided alternatives
- Verified the built user interface against the user needs and business goals

## **LANGUAGES**





**ENGLISH** 

**GERMAN** 



#### **EDUCATION**

2009 - 2015 B.A. & M.A. Architecture **UACEG University, Sofia Bulgaria** 

2004 - 2009 Gymnasium First English Language School Sofia, Bulgaria

#### **HOBBIES**













**READING** SKIING

### **MORE EXPERIENCE**

# **UX/UI Designer, Researcher UX certification course by CareerFoundry**

Figma

Sketch

Usability Hub

Google Forms

UX Design of a case study for a finance app that helps users operate hasslefree with their money & bank accounts.

- Conducted competitive analysis, user interviews and surveyed 140 participants to gather valuable research data and develop evidence-based hypotheses, personas, user journeys, user flows and sitemap
- Designed interactive prototype and performed usability testing
- Established extensive Style Guide & Pattern Library for future development
- Built simple and flexible Atomic UI components in Figma

## **UX/UI Designer, Freelance Relaxify App for customer Actegro**

06.2020 - 01.2021

07.2021 - 12.2021

Adobe XD

Miro

Photoshop

Design of a scientifically based app for mental fitness with statistics, exercises and surveys. MVP Release - 02.2021

- Facilitated a discovery workshop aiming to look at the product from different prospective and gather requirements
- Created information architecture, wireframes and high-fidelity prototypes with focus on simple and intuitive design

## **UX/UI Designer, Freelance Kellner App, Competition**

04.2020 - 05.2020

Adobe XD

Photoshop

As part of a competition designed an app that helps people easily order and pay for their food in restaurants.

- Analyzed the existing user journey and user experience
- · Designed new user flows, identified personas and touchpoints
- Created the screen designs and interactive prototypes using Adobe XD

#### 10.2019 - 03.2020**UX/UI Designer. Freelance Responsive webseite for Azure Cloud Engineer**

Adobe XD

Photoshop

Usability Hub

The task included the creation of mobile-first responsive design for the website of a freelance cloud engineer. Release 06.2020

- Analyzed competing websites to create a suitable and customer-focused information architecture
- Designed wireframes and interactive high-fidelity prototypes
- Executed usability tests and used the results to improve the emphasis on the most important information

## **SKILLS**

#### Tools\*

Sketch Figma

Adobe XD

Photoshop

Illustrator

Miro Jira

Confluence

Zeplin **Abstract**  After Effects

Usability Hub

## Soft skills

Creativity Communication

Team work Structure

Empathy

Solution orientation

Attention to detail

<sup>\*</sup> The list is not complete and includes only my favorite tools for each purpose. If you are using other tools, get in touch and we will discuss how I can best help you.